Patrick McKnight

(925) 266-7132 | patrickgmcknight@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

Objective

My objective is to find a role in coding or web development. I have 7 years of professional experience in the supply chain industry. However, I am currently completing a coding bootcamp through UCSD extended studies - you can see what I've been working on in the course here.

Topics covered in my bootcamp course include: GitHub, VS Code, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React JS, Node JS, Express JS, 3rd Party APIs, RESTful APIs, Server Side APIs, Web APIs, Object Oriented Programming (OOP), SQL, NoSQL, Object-Relational Mapping (ORM), Model-View-Controller (MVC), Intro to Computer Science, and MERN.

Projected Course Completion Date: June 5th, 2023

During my professional experience in the supply chain industry I have had to find creative solutions, managed working on teams of a variety of sizes, worked with tight deadlines, adapted to substantial changes in a short time, quickly and clearly shared verbal updates, and managed working on reduced teams with high work volume.

While I'm still learning the technical aspect of coding I believe my skill set, ability to quickly learn, and ability to adapt make me an ideal candidate for your role. I'm excited about the possibility of working on your team and look forward to hearing back from you soon.

Patrick McKnight

(925) 266-7132 | patrickgmcknight@gmail.com | San Diego, CA

Education

California State University, East Bay - Hayward, CA
Bachelor of Arts, Business Administration - Business Management (Marketing)
University of California, San Diego - La Jolla, CA
Bootcamp - Full Stack Web Development

Work Experience

Sr. Supply Planner

March 2022 - January 2023

Premier Nutrition Corporation - Emeryville, CA

- Skills that transfer to full stack web developer roles:
 - o Efficiently prioritized high volume of work independently and created my own deadlines.
 - o Led communication with internal and external partners to achieve desired results.
 - o Took the initiative on important conversations and came prepared with creative solutions.
 - o Communicated with my manager and upper management when assistance was needed.

Supply Planner

January 2021 - January 2022

Woodbolt Distribution LLC dba Nutrabolt - Austin, TX

- Skills that transfer to entry-level web developer roles:
 - o Maintained clear processes and documented changes to processes throughout my work.
 - o Independently created tools that would benefit my role and the company as a whole.
 - o Led weekly calls with external partners to allow for clear communication on both sides.

Supply Planning Analyst

April 2019 - January 2021

Petco Animal Supplies, Inc. - San Diego, CA

- Skills that transfer to full stack web developer roles:
 - o Successfully managed the largest volume of work within the role in the company.
 - o Independently met with vendors when communication was unclear and set up recurring meetings with vendors that had consistent communication challenges.
 - o Worked cross-functionally with many internal partners to ensure all department goals were considered in our approach.
 - o Successfully navigated planned and unplanned challenges due to COVID related impacts.
 - o Achieved higher KPIs metrics than all others working within the same role.

Inventory & Fulfillment Operations Manager

August 2016 – March 2019

Grinds Coffee Pouches - Oakland, CA

- Skills that transfer to full stack web developer roles:
 - o Balanced responsibilities across many different areas of the business, wore many hats.
 - o Proactively implemented changes that benefitted the entire company and those working with me.
 - o Organized and led meetings with upper management to discuss important topics and actively sought out feedback to improve my way of working and communicating updates.
 - o Independently and proactively created tools to better organize my workload and solve problems that impacted the entire business.

Student-Athlete: Intercollegiate Baseball Team

September 2014 – June 2016

California State University, East Bay - Hayward, CA

• Balanced 30+ hours/week of practice, competitions, study hall, training, and travel with a rigorous class schedule. Set and achieved both team and individual goals while performing in high-pressure situations.